# Steven Berrisford

stevenberrisford@gmail.com
(+44) 07891078922
github.com/StevenB96 || stevenberrisford.com
www.linkedin.com/in/steven-berrisford-55061a134/



I am a highly motivated and diligent software developer, eager to contribute my skills to a Mid-Level software development position or a comparable role. With 3 years of solid experience, I have the expertise to quickly make a positive impact. Here is a short summary:

- o 3 years full stack experience as a: React developer, React Native developer, and Laravel developer.
- o 2+ years experience as a: Python developer, Node developer including: Django framework, Express framework.
- o Excellent skills in Amazon Web Services, Docker Containers, Kubernetes, and Terraform Infrastructure as Code.
- o Ability to mentor juniors and present latest developments and trends in Software Development and DevOps.
- o Track record of building connections with internal stakeholders and fostering a collaborative environment.

# **WORK EXPERIENCE**

# Scorchsoft Ltd: Junior Developer (09/2020 - 07/2022) | Mid-Level Developer (07/2022 - 09/2023)

As a junior working in a dynamic small business, I contributed to ~10 projects for diverse customers. Responsibilities included clarifying requirements, estimating work packages, designing/building full stack web/mobile applications, and testing prior to Quality Assurance. I managed tasks using Kanban and followed both Agile and Waterfall methodologies, which gave me a comprehensive understanding of the Software Development Life Cycle. Additionally, as a Mid-Level I assigned tasks, mentored juniors, joined customer meetings, and was more involved in decision making.

Selected Projects			
Sector	Details		
Medical	As primary developer for a new development phase of an existing mobile application and new full		
(5 months)	stack web application. I adapted to new technologies, learned to work with Java and adjusted to new internal processes. Additionally, the opportunity to deploy the full stack application on AWS EC2 expanded my knowledge of Cloud deployment.		
Diplomacy (7 months)	As the primary developer from inception, I developed the MVP. I was challenged with working with a new junior developer and a junior project assistant. I mentored both, assigned tasks, provided guidance, and clarified requirements. The project required me to perform ETL operations on data from an external API and integrate geolocation services. The app is available on major platforms.		

#### **EDUCATION AND TRAINING**

# Post-University Training

# Skills Bootcamp in Cloud (AWS), Cenit College, October 2023 - February 2024

I gained a detailed understanding of the AWS Cloud. The course covered concepts such as shared responsibility, access management, security, deployment, operations, billing, and activities such as quizzes and practical tasks - including a main project. Alongside the course, I undertook a major personal project and gave a presentation to the group.

# Full Stack Web Development Course, Futureproof, March 2020 - June 2020

I gained a comprehensive understanding of databases, programming languages, frameworks, APIs, machine learning and more. Throughout the course, I worked on several mini-projects developing collaboration skills. We presented our final projects to potential employers which improved my employability skills and eventually led me to my first job.

# University

# 1st Class Master's Degree in Mechanical Engineering, University of Exeter, 2015 - 2019

The basis for my final project was studying the thermal impact of phase change materials in buildings using computational modeling and applied machine learning. The degree also included advanced mathematics and business studies, providing me with a strong foundation for diverse career opportunities. I received a dean's commendation.

#### Research Bursary, University of Exeter, May 2018 - August 2018

Working with a small group of researchers, I helped to develop a system for generating extreme weather for use in building simulation. The work involved Imputation, Copula statistics, Fast Fourier Transforms and Genetic Algorithms, which were applied using MATLAB. The Research Bursary enhanced my basic coding and problem-solving abilities.

# **IT Qualifications**

Certification	Certification Body
AWS Cloud Practitioner	Amazon Web Services
Intermediate Certificate in Enterprise and Solution Architecture	British Computer Society

# SKILLS AND KNOWLEDGE

Programming Languages: JavaScript, PHP, Python, HTML, CSS, SQL, Bash, Java.

Packages: React, React Native, Laravel, Yii2, Django, Flask, Node, Jest, Mocha, Pytest, Unittest, Socket.IO.

Working methodologies: Agile, BDD, FDD, Test Driven Development, Waterfall Development.

Databases (Brands/Types): Relational, NoSQL, Graph, MySQL, PostgreSQL, MongoDB.

Data Science: NumPy, Pandas, SciPy, Scikit Learn, Matplotlib, MATLAB.

DevOps Tools: Git, Docker, Kubernetes, Terraform, Bitbucket, Jira, OpenVPN.

Cloud Tools: Route53, ECS, EC2, CodePipeline, ECR, CloudFormation.

# PERSONAL PROJECTS FOR PRIVATE INTEREST

http://stevenberrisford.com/projects			
Movie	A Python web/ETL application deployed with Docker on AWS Infrastructure (ECS, Lambda, S3,		
Predictor	CodePipeline). Built on Flask (web framework), Scikit Learn (ML library) and Matplotlib (graphing tool).		
Diagram	A React (JavaScript web framework) diagram builder/optimiser. The focus is the custom ML		
Optimiser	optimisation algorithm. The project is also a demonstration of animation and state management.		
Web	A scalable, comprehensively unit tested, MVC application built using Django (Python web framework).		
Library	It is deployed on a Kubernetes cluster (DevOps tool), integrating with database microservices.		
Terraform	A containerised full stack application built using Express and React (JavaScript web frameworks). It		
Visualiser	queries a Kubernetes API to visualise Clusters that have been deployed on AWS using Terraform.		
Shared	A full stack application built using Express and React (JavaScript web frameworks). It implements		
Whiteboard	Socket.IO (TCP sockets) and Konva (draw package) to stream line strokes between connected clients.		

# **TESTEMONIALS**

Quote	Name	Role
Steven made an impression with his exceptional proficiency.	Audrius Dobrovolskis, Scorchsoft	Lead Developer
Steven is very easy to get along with and a great presence.	Jordan Smith, Scorchsoft	Mid-level Developer

# **OUTSIDE OF WORK**

Hobbies: Running, Dancing (Salsa, Bachata and Swing), Singing (Choir) Languages: Norwegian, German (B1) Swedish (A2) French, Portuguese (A1)